Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities reports and other material
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections
Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities reports and other material
1923-1972
Xavier University Archives and Special Collections Phone: 513-745-4821 http://www.xavier.edu/cm/archives
Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities
2.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
This is a collection of publications, reports, and correspondence sent to the President of Xavier University by the Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities (previously known as the Jesuit Educational Association). Some Xavier-specific correspondence is included in the collection.
XUA-84
History of Association Jesuit Colleges and Universities, formerly the Jesuit Educational Association
The Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities was created in 1970.
The Jesuit Educational Association was a national organization comprised of all the Jesuit secondary and post-secondary schools in the United States. In 1970 it divided into two organizations, the Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities (AJCU) and the Jesuit Secondary Education Association (JSEA). According to the website of AJCU, the Jesuit Educational Association came into existence in 1936, although it seems to have existed on a regional level as early as 1923.
Scope and Content
This collection includes documents including correspondence, bulletins, reports, questionnaires, surveys, minutes, and proceedings of various conferences. The earliest item of JEA item is dated 1923, the latest 1970. The earliest AJCU item is from 1970, the latest from 1972.
Statement of Arrangement
Materials are arranged chronologically into folders.
Restrictions on Access
Some materials may have restricted access. Please contact the archives staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Subjects:
Jesuits--Education (Higher)-- United States; Jesuits--Education (Secondary)-- United States
Organizations/Corporations:
Jesuit Educational Association; Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Jesuit Educational Association. Mid-West Division. Proceedings of the Second Annual Convention, 1923 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Jesuit Educational Association. Mid-West Division. Proceedings of the Sixth Annual Convention., 1927 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Jesuit Educational Association. Central States Division. Proceedings of the Eighth Annual Convention, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Jesuit Educational Association. Central States Division. Proceedings of the Ninth Annual Convention., 1930 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Jesuit Educational Association. Central States Division. Proceedings of the Tenth Annual Convention, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Reports, Minutes, 1932; 1938-1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Reports, Proceedings, Minutes, Bulletins, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Bulletins, Reports, Minutes, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Bulletins, Reports, Minutes, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Bulletins, Reports, Minutes, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Bulletins, Records, Minutes, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Bulletins, Reports, Minutes, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Jesuit Educational Association Constitution, Correspondence, Bulletins, Reports, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Jesuit Educational Association Future of Jesuit Education in the United States, Undated; Carbon copy of typescript manuscript. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  The author and date of this manuscript are not known. It was possibly created in the 1950's.
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Bulletins, Reports, Minutes, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Proceedings, Reports, Bulletins, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Jesuit Educational Association Proceedings of Conferences of Presidents, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Jesuit Educational Association Proceedings of Conferences of Presidents, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Jesuit Educational Association Proceedings of Conferences of Presidents, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Jesuit Educational Association Proceedings, Correspondence, Bulletins, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Jesuit Educational Association Los Angeles Workshop on Philosophy and Theology, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Jesuit Educational Association Proceedings of Conference of Presidents, Bulletins, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Reports, Bulletins, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Jesuit Educational Association Proceedings of the Conference of Presidents, 1964 January (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Jesuit Educational Association Proceedings of Conference of Presidents, 1964 August (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Jesuit Educational Association Report on Questionnaire Study of Jesuit Colleges and Universities, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Jesuit Educational Association Proceedings of Conference of Presidents, Bulletins, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Jesuit Educational Association Salary Study, Bulletins, Correspondence, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Reports, Bulletins (part 1), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Reports, Bulletins (Part 2), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Reports, Bulletins (Part 3), 1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Jesuit Educational Association Jesuit Research Council of America, Bulletins, Correspondence, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Reports, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Jesuit Educational Association Jesuit Commission on Colleges and Universities, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Jesuit Educational Association Constitution, Correspondence, Reports, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Jesuit Educational Association Jesuit Commission on Colleges and Universities, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Jesuit Educational Association Correspondence, Papers, Reports, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Jesuit Educational Association Denver Workshop on Higher Education, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Jesuit Educational Association Jesuit Commission on Colleges and Universities, Correspondence, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Jesuit Educational Association Jesuit Commission on Colleges and Universities, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities Introduction of the Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities Correspondence, Reports, Constitution of AJCU, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities Cessna "Mask of Divestiture and Disaffiliation": Legal Opinions, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities AJCU Board of Directors Minutes, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Association of Jesuit Colleges and Universities Correspondence, Compensation Report, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)